Register of the Archives of the Soviet communist party and Soviet state microfilm collection: Russian State Archive of Contemporary History (Rossiiskii gosudarstvennyi arkhiv noveishei istorii - RGANI)
Hoover Institution Archives
- Fond 89, Communist Party of the Soviet Union on Trial records, 1919-1992; 24 reels (Reel 1.989-1.1012)
  - Opis 76
    - Cover letter to the TsK KPSS from V. Zhurkin, Deputy Director of the Institute for the Study of the United States of America and Canada, submitting the analytical memorandum Reagan's Approach to the Madrid Conference and the "Human Rights Problem"; the memorandum analyzing possible changes in American foreign policy under the Reagan administration and speculating on the influence of those changes on the Madrid meeting; brief note signed by R. Bogdanov, directing the material to V. Kobysh (Department of International Information), 1980 December (Opis 76, Reel 1.1012, File 69)
    - Cover letter to L. Zamiatin, Chief of the Department of International Information, from A. Dobrynin, Soviet Ambassador to the United States, submitting a report on informational and propagandist work of the Soviet Embassy in the United States and a plan entitled Plan for Informational and Propagandist Measures to be Taken by the Embassy in 1981; the report outlining the main actions of the Embassy, describing the propagandist and ideological situation in the United States, anti-Soviet campaigns in the American press, possible propagandist and ideological actions to be taken by the new Reagan administration, listing the main informational and propagandist measures taken in the United States by the Soviet Embassy, outlining propaganda measures taken by the Soviet Embassy in the press and in the American media, oral propaganda,cooperation with public organizations, use of television, film distribution, records, and philately for propaganda purposes, drawing conclusions, and offering proposals for future work, 1981 January (Opis 76, Reel 1.1012, File 70)
    - Cover letter to the TsK KPSS from G. Arbatov, Director of the Institute for the Study of the United States of America and Canada, submitting excerpts from the memoranda of conversations held in the Institute with K. Lipper(?), senior partner of the Salomon Brothers company and Professor at Columbia University; the excerpts from the memoranda re Lipper's opinions on prices for oil and determinants influencing pricing in this area, on the production of synthetic fuel in the United States and the policy of the US government toward this problem, on interest rates and the dollar exchange rate, and on the Reagan administration and its foreign policy, 1981 August (Opis 76, Reel 1.1012, File 71)
    - Memorandum to the TsK KPSS from L. Zamiatin, Chief of the Department of Political Propaganda Abroad, summarizing the main issues of a new program for modernization of US strategic weapons, presented in the statement of President Reagan on October, 2, 1981, 1981 October (Opis 76, Reel 1.1012, File 72)